DENIZ MEVLEVIOGLU PhD Candidate

Profile —

A Computer Science PhD candidate at University College Cork, researching real-time anxiety prediction in Virtual Reality Exposure Therapy. Research interests include on-body physiological sensors, machine learning and Virtual Reality. Experienced tutor and demonstrator for varying topics in Computer Science such as web development, authoring and 3D modelling.

_____ Contact ____

Address: Western Gateway Building 1.12

1:1 Honours

Western Road, Cork

Email: <u>d.mevlevioglu@cs.ucc.ie</u>

Website: denizmev.com

Education -

2020–2024 **PhD in Computer Science**, *University College Cork*

Thesis title: "Real-time Anxiety prediction in Virtual Reality

Exposure Therapy"

2018–2019 MSc in Interactive Media, University College Cork

Thesis title: "Visual respiratory feedback in virtual reality"

2012–2016 BA in Psychology, Bahcesehir University 2.94 GPA

Publications –

Deniz Mevlevioğlu, Sabin Tabirca, and David Murphy. 2021. Emotional Virtual Reality Stroop Task: Pilot Design. In Proceedings of the 27th ACM Symposium on Virtual Reality Software and Technology (VRST '21). Association for Computing Machinery, New York, NY, USA, Article 66, 1–3. DOI:

10.1145/3489849.3489952

Deniz Mevlevioğlu, David Murphy, and Sabin Tabirca. 2021. Visual Respiratory Feedback in Virtual Reality Exposure Therapy: A Pilot Study. In ACM International Conference on Interactive Media Experiences (IMX '21), June 21–23, 2021, Virtual Event, USA. ACM, New York, NY, USA 6 Pages. DOI:

10.1145/3452918.3458799

Deniz Mevlevioğlu, David Murphy, and Sabin Tabirca. 2021. In Real-time Anxiety Prediction in Virtual Reality Exposure Therapy. in Adjunct Proceedings of the ACM IMX '21, June 21–23, 2021, New York City, US. DOI: 10.6084/m9.figshare.14699751.v1

ACM SIGCHI The Special Interest Group on Computer – Human Interaction

IEEE WIE Women in Engineering

Other Education _____

2020 **Research Integration**, Epigeum by Oxford University Press

Specialty Training: Human subjects protection

2018 **Pedagogical Formation**, Marmara University

Experience -

2020-Present

Tutor, Munster Programming Training by University College Cork

Topics: + Web Development and Design + Databases

Responsibilities:

- Delivered lectures to two classes of approximately 40 secondary school students over the course of 10 weeks
- Provided hands-on tutorials with multiple exercises
- Assigned and graded assignments

Skills and technologies: -HTML -CSS -JavaScript -SQL -MySQL -PHP -Apache

2019-Present

Demonstrator, School of Computer Science, University College Cork

Topics: + Web Development + Authoring + 3D Graphics and Modelling + Graphics + Future and Emerging Interaction Technologies +Human-Computer Interaction +Internet-based applications **Responsibilities:**

- Demonstrated for practical sessions to a class of approximately 40 MSc students over the course of one semester
- Delivered tutorials in various topics
- Helped students with problem solving

Skills and technologies: -Virtual Reality -Python -Java -HTML -CSS -JavaScript -PHP -Blender -jQuery -three.js -WebGL

2019-2020

Web Developer, Freelance

Responsibilities:

- Developed and deployed custom personal and e-commerce websites using
- Worked with web designers to synchronize web presence with brand identity and
- Employed search engine optimization tactics to increase reach of targeted audience.

Skills and technologies: -WordPress -HTML -CSS -JavaScript -PHP

2019

Tutor, School of Arts and Humanities, University College Cork

Topic: Concepts and Collaboration in Digital Humanities

Responsibilities:

- Delivered step-by-step tutorials on how to set up a personal website to a class of approximately 40 BA students
- Introduced and familiarised students with technologies useful for academia
- Helped students with problem solving

Skills and technologies: -WordPress -HTML -CSS -Zotero

Activities -

Student Volunteer Chair, ACM IMX 2022

Acted as a member of the organising committee for ACM Interactive Media Experiences, the leading international conference for research into interactive media experiences.

Guest Lecturer, *University College Cork*

Delivered a guest lecture with the topic "Using Python for Scripting in Blender" to MSc Interactive Media Students, including a tutorial.

Member of Team Xhalers, VR4Rehab Hackathon

Worked with a team of physiotherapists, nurses, physicians and other computer scientists to design and prototype "Short games for long covid"; a VR application for aiding in the management of long-covid symptoms in the VR4Rehab hackathon by Interreg.

Skills —

Academic Research

- Virtual Reality
- Virtual RealityMachine Learning
- Tutoring
- Web Development

———— Technologies

- Python
- HTML
- CSS
- JS

- PHP
- Turkish (Native)

Languages

• English (Bilingual)

Unity • C#

- Keras
- BlenderTensorFlow
- Java SKLearn • Three.js Git
- MySQL